<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xml:id="intro"
  version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
  xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
  xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">

  <title>Introduction</title>

  <para>
    The difference of this book and other books about programming is about helping programmers to be more effective.
    Let's think about the elements which makes an programmer effective. They includes the deep understanding about tools
    (consider programming languages, code libraries or platforms as tools), design knowledge and domain knowledge.
    There are already books about programming languages, libraries, platforms, designing and domain. All these books
    can help programmers to be more effective, but there is still a need for a book which will help developers to
    utilize the tools effectively though the phases of the project. A book which contains best practices
    collected by experienced programmers to help the reader to avoid commons traps and improve productivity.
    The book should also be a reference book to show programmers the best way to resolve the common issues. It should
    be practical, specific and easy to understand and follow. Of course a book like that will be hard to be kept up to date
    because of the development environment changing everyday. But it would be most useful.
    This book will try to achieve these targets as much as possible. And you, as a reader, will decide if the
    book has completed the mission or not.
  </para>

  <para>The book includes the following chapters
    <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="intro" /></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="devenv" /></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="program" /></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="debug" /></para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para><xref linkend="optimize" /></para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
  </para>

</chapter>
