<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<preface xml:id="preface"
  version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
  xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
  xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">

  <title>Preface</title>

  <para>
    I still remember about the first days when I learned Java about ten years ago. I used
    <productname>Notepad</productname> to write my first Java programs and used
    <command>javac</command> to compile them. And I used <function>System.out.println()</function>
    to debug my programs. I have to admit that learning Java was not an easy thing and today it is still very difficult.
    I think that programming will never be an easy thing even when we already have many powerful tools in hand.
    Because the expect of users for software systems will be more and more.
  </para>

  <para>
    Everyday I still meet many people who is new to Java and they often ask me programming
    questions. I feel like seeing myself again writing Java in <productname>Notepad</productname>,
    compiling using <command>javac</command> and debugging using <function>System.out.println()</function>.
    To share my working experience with Java, I decided to write down something to make the life
    of new Java programmers easier. And the result is the book you are reading. Although writing is not my strong
    ability (I am a programmer, after all). I also know that sharing knowledge (even with a lot of grammar mistakes)
    is still better than doing nothing. And I hope you can agree with me on this.
  </para>

  <para>
    The chapters of this book is organized in the order which software project phases will happen. In this way you will
    be able to find what you need easily. Each chapter will show you how to resolve common issues.
    Note that there are other ways to resolve these issues which might be better in the ways documented in the book.
    So write me and let me know your comments so I can share your experiences with people in next revision of this book.
  </para>

  <para>
    It is enough for an introduction. Let the journey started!
  </para>

</preface>
