<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xml:id="devenv"
  version="5.0" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
  xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude"
  xmlns:db="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">

  <title>Development Environment</title>

  <para>
    The first (and may be the most difficult) thing at the beginning of a project is to set up the development
    environment. An effective and easy to use environment will save time and reduce potential bugs.
  </para>

  <section>
    <title>Eclipse IDE</title>
    <para>Eclipse IDE is a free, popular and powerful IDE. There are useful plug-ins which can be integrated
      into Eclipse so you can have more power. The following section will guide you through the steps to set up an
      Eclipse IDE with various useful features.</para>
    <note>
        <para>A recommended way to build an Eclipse-based IDE for the development team is to begin with an original Eclipse build
         (I often use "Eclipse IDE for Java EE Developers" build) and start to put all plugins to eclipse/dropins folder then zip it again. 
         This way will create a typical environment for new team members and still allow experts to customize the environment if needed 
         (i.e. removing unnecessary plugins in dropins/ folder).</para>
        <para>How to isolate the plugin files to put into dropins folder: just unzip a "Eclipse IDE for Java EE Developers" build 
        and install the plugin using site update URL, then use WinMerge tool to compare the features and plugins folders with 
        original folders, copy the new files/folders to a separate folder, rename folder and copy this folder to dropins/. For example, my dropins folder often contains
        the following folders: dropins/checkstyle/features/, dropins/checkstyle/plugins/, dropins/others/plugins/,.. etc.</para>
    </note>

    <section>
      <title>AnyEdits plug-in</title>
      <para>AnyEdits is a very useful plug-in.</para>
    </section>

  </section>


</chapter>
